# AMIRA RAMADAN

## **GIS SPECAILST**

+201144679767

ramadan.amira@rocketmail.com

LinkedIn: amira-ramadan-GISSpecialist 🖘

Portfolio: AmiraRamadan23 🖘



Seeking an entry-level position in the field of GIS that help me utilize my university and internship experience to gather, analysis, manage data in a project from start to finish.

## **INTERNSHIP**

**4/2022 TO PRESENT** 

## GEOMATICES TRACK- INTENSIVE CODE CAMP, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY INSTITUTE

I am creating a tool to query, analyze and map data in GIS packages such as ARCGIS Desktop, ARCGIS pro. I am developing geo-spatial solutions using the lasted technologies.

11/2020 TO 1/2021

## **ACCOUNT MANAGER TRANIEE, THE PORTAL AGANCY**

I was responsible of managing a company's relationships with its customers, assist with marking team, handling client complaints, collecting and analyzing data, and improving the overall customer experience.

#### **FREELANCE**

#### **1/2021 TO PRESENT**

## GIS SPECALIST, MOSTAQEL.COM ↔

I am designing digital maps using geospatial data and analyze spatial and non-spatial information.

#### **5/2021 TO PRESENT**

#### GIS SPECALIST, UPWORK ↔

I am designing digital maps using geospatial data and analyze spatial and non-spatial information.

#### 8/2021 TO 10/2021

#### **DATA COLLECTOR,** THE DATUM COMPANY

I collected the data from Google my map and put these data at Excel sheet.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

11/2021 TO 12/2021

## **GEOMATICES ENGENNER, MICRO ENGINEERING TECH INC**

I exacted point features from point cloud that output of laser scanning at TOPODOT and line features at TBC.

2/2021 TO 3/2021

## **ADMINISTRATOR (PART TIME), THE PORTAL AGANCY**

I was responsible of answering incoming calls; taking messages and re-directing calls, taking minute, data entry and help marking team to bring new idea of companies.

## **TRAINING**

#### 10/2019 TO 12/2019

## TRANIEE, GOUZOUR FOUNDTION

I was a trainee in woman Employment and Empowerment (WEE) scholarship-provided by Japanese Embassy, Including:

- -Business English training (108 hours).
- -ICT training (72 hours).
- -Soft skills training (48 hours).
- -Career coaching (24 hours).

## 24/6/2018 TO 29/6/2018

# **GIS & REMOTE SENSING TRAINEE,** THE NATIONAL AUTHORITY FOR REMOTE SENSING & SPACE

I learned fundamentals of GIS and applied it in ARCMAP, fundamentals of Remote sensing and applied it in ERDAS.

#### 7/2016 TO 8/2016

## **SURVEYING TRAINEE, THE ARAB CONTRACTORS**

I trained on how use total station and balance and how make land points.

#### **EDUCATION**

10/2020 TO 8/2021

# VOCATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEM DIPLOMA, FACULTY OF AFRICAN POSTGRADUATE STUDIES, CAIRO UNIVERSITY

Very Good (85%), Graduate project (excellent) ↔

9/2015 TO 7/ 2019

## B.C OF GEOGRAPHY DEPARTMENT (ENIVORMENT ISOLATION) FACULTY OF ARTS,

**HELWAN UNIVERSITY** 

Good (72%), Graduate project (excellent) ↔

## **TECHENCAIL SKILLS**

- ARCGIS Desktop
- QGIS
- Erads Image& ENVIE
- HTML & CSS

- JavaScript
- python
- ARCGIS ONLINE
- ARCGIS pro

## **COURSES**

7/2020 TO 8/2020

21 DAYS GIS ONLINE TRAINING USING QGIS, DEPARTMENT GEOGRAPHY, SCHOOL OF

EARTH SCIENCES, CENTRAL UNIVERSITY OF KARNATAKA, INDIA

2/2019 TO 4/2020

FUNDAMENTALS OF GIS & GIS FORMATS, DESIGN AND QUALITY, COURSERA

9/2018 TO 8/2019

ENGLISH COURSE, LEVELS A2C-B1A, AUC

8/2017 TO 6/2018

GIS LEVEL (1,2), HELWAN UNIVERSITY

7/2018

**CARTOGRAPHY, ESRI ONLINE** 

2/2018

INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER PROGRAMMING, KOREAN CULTURE CENTER

## VOUNTEERING

#### 6/2022 TO PRESENT

## **AMBASSADOR, HERE MAP CREATOR EXPERT**

I am making edits and updates at online map using editing tool known as Map Creator.

## 4/2021 TO 12/2021

#### **SOCIAL MEDIA VOLUNTEER, AFRICAN WOMEN IN GIS**

I was responsible of writing posts at different platforms such as LinkedIn, Twitter.

#### **6/2020 TO PRESENT**

#### **MAPPER, MISSING MAP**

I am making edits, updates, draws roads and buildings at online map for organizations at Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team (HOT) platform.

#### 2/2020 TO 9/2020

## **PUBIUC RELATIONS SPECIALIST, YLE FOUNDATION**

I was responsible for using multiple media channels; press, social medial, email newsletters and online content production, events and networking.

#### **1/2020 TO PRESENT**

## MAPPER, HUMANITARIAN OPENSTREETMAP TEAM (HOT)

I am making edits, updates, draws roads and buildings in online map for organization at Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team (HOT) platform.

#### 5/2019 TO 9/2021

#### **ORGANIZER, RESALA CHARITY ORGANIZATION**

I was responsible for organizing courses, dealing with trainers and handling students.